RG 002:025, Bipartisan Senate Committee of Review
Connecticut State Library
Bipartisan Senate Committee of Review records
1974-2007, bulk 2007
2007
Connecticut State Library
Connecticut. General Assembly. Bipartisan Senate Committee of Review
1 cubic foot
The Senate created the Committee in August 2007 to review Sen. Louis DeLuca's actions leading up to his guilty plea on a misdemeanor threatening charge.
RG002_025_BSCR
2008-029
Historical Note
The Senate created the Committee in August 2007 to review Sen. Louis DeLuca's actions leading up to his guilty plea on a misdemeanor threatening charge. Sen. DeLuca resigned his office effective November 30, 2007.
Scope and Content
Includes meeting material such as agendas, minutes, transcripts and handouts; procedures; correspondence and responses; and resolutions.
Index Terms
Organizations:
Connecticut. General Assembly. Bipartisan Senate Committee of Review
Persons:
DeLuca, Louis, 1933-
Subjects:
Connecticut. General Assembly. Bipartisan Senate Committee of Review -- Records and correspondence; Connecticut. General Assembly. Senate -- Discipline; Threats of violence -- Connecticut; Misconduct in office -- Connecticut; Legislators -- Connecticut -- Discipline
Document Types:
Agendas; Correspondence; DVDs; Minutes; Reports; Resolutions (administrative records); Transcripts
Restrictions on Access
These records are stored at an off-site facility and therefore may not be available on a same-day basis.
See the policy.
Alternative Form Available
These documents are available from the Connecticut General Assembly website at.
Container List
- Series 1. Administrative Records, 2007
  - Affidavits, 2007 May 30, October 15-29 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Agendas, 2007 August 27 - November 13 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Appointments made by Sen. DeLuca, 2007 September 4 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 2007 August 22 - November 7 (Box 1, Folder 4-8)
  - Extension, 2007 October 5 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Meeting handouts, 2007 October 15 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Minutes, 2007 August 28 - November 13 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - News clippings, 2007 August 23-27 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Press releases, 2007 August-October (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Procedures, 2007 September 4 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Resolution, 2007 June Special Session (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Timeline, 2007 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    Lists events from 2001 to 2007.
- Series 2. Meeting Transcripts, 2007
  - Meeting transcript, 2007 August 28 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Meeting transcript, 2007 September 6 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Meeting transcript, 2007 September 19 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Meeting transcript, 2007 October 4 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Meeting transcript, 2007 October 15 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Meeting transcript, 2007 November 1 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Meeting transcript, 2007 November 6 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Meeting transcript, 2007 November 13 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Series 3. Reports, 2007
  - Office of Legislative Research (OLR) and Legislative Commissioners' Office (LCO) reports: Discipline actions in other states' legislative bodies, 2007 September 17 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Office of Legislative Research (OLR) and Legislative Commissioners' Office (LCO) reports: Discipline actions in other states' legislative bodies, 2007 October 2 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Office of Legislative Research (OLR) and Legislative Commissioners' Office (LCO) reports: Legislative disciplinary actions in other states involving uncharged conduct, 2007 October 4 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Office of Legislative Research (OLR) and Legislative Commissioners' Office (LCO) reports: Discipline actions in other states' legislative bodies, 2007 October 11 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Miscellaneous reports, 1974-2006 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Series 4. Videos, 2007
  Copies of these videos are available in the State Library's CT-N collection.
  The videos are stored separate from the collection. Contact State Archives staff for assistance.
  - "Senate Minority Leader Louis DeLuca Public Statement", 2007 June 4; 1 DVD
  - "Capitol News Briefing with Democratic Legislative Leaders on Budget and Session Issues", 2007 June 7; 1 DVD
  - "Capitol News Briefing with State Senator Louis DeLuca Following Senate vote to Reivew His Actions", 2007 August 22; 1 DVD